Reinhold Niebuhr Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Reinhold Niebuhr Papers 1907-1997 1930-1990
MSS34751
Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1892-1971
16,250 items
70 containers plus 1 oversize
28 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Theologian, philosopher, and author. Correspondence, speeches, sermons, lectures, articles, book reviews, typescripts of books and articles, family papers, subject files, biographical material, bibliographies, photographs, and memorabilia reflecting Niebuhr's influence on twentieth-century theology, politics, and society and his efforts to apply religious and ethical standards to modern social and political problems including labor and race relations.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Amiran, David H. K., 1910- --Correspondence.; Amiran, Ruth--Correspondence.; Auden, W. H. (Wystan Hugh), 1907-1973--Correspondence.; Barnes, John, 1917-1992--Correspondence.; Barzun, Jacques, 1907-2012--Correspondence.; Benn, Tony, 1925-2014--Correspondence.; Bennett, John C. (John Coleman), 1902-1995--Correspondence.; Berlin, Isaiah, 1909-1997--Correspondence.; Bingham, Jonathan B.--Correspondence.; Bingham, June, 1919-2007--Correspondence.; Bingham, June, 1919-2007. Courage to change: an introduction to the life and thought of Reinhold Niebuhr. 1961.; Bonhoeffer, Dietrich, 1906-1945--Correspondence.; Carter, Jimmy, 1924- --Correspondence.; Clark, Tom C. (Tom Campbell), 1899-1977--Correspondence.; Clasper, Paul D.--Correspondence.; Coffin, Henry Sloane, 1877-1954--Correspondence.; Conant, James Bryant, 1893-1978--Correspondence.; Cripps, Isobel, 1891-1979--Correspondence.; Cripps, Richard Stafford, Sir, 1889-1952--Correspondence.; Eddy, Sherwood, 1871-1963--Correspondence.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969--Correspondence.; Eliot, T. S. (Thomas Stearns), 1888-1965--Correspondence.; Fox, Richard Wightman, 1945-; Frankfurter, Felix, 1882-1965--Correspondence.; Franklin, Sam H.--Correspondence.; Gordon, J. King--Correspondence.; Gordon, Ruth Anderson--Correspondence.; Hall, Ronald O. (Ronald Owen)--Correspondence.; Herberg, Will--Correspondence.; Humphrey, Hubert H. (Hubert Horatio), 1911-1978--Correspondence.; Hutchins, Robert Maynard, 1899-1977--Correspondence.; Kennan, George F. (George Frost), 1904-2005--Correspondence.; Kollek, Teddy, 1911-2007--Correspondence.; Littell, Franklin H. (Franklin Hamlin), 1917-2009--Correspondence.; MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-1982--Correspondence.; Mailer, Norman--Correspondence.; Marty, Martin E., 1928- --Correspondence.; McGovern, George S. (George Stanley), 1922-2012--Correspondence.; Mead, Margaret, 1901-1978--Correspondence.; Morgenthau, Hans J. (Hans Joachim), 1904-1980--Correspondence.; Moynihan, Daniel P. (Daniel Patrick), 1927-2003--Correspondence.; Niebuhr family.; Niebuhr, H. Richard (Helmut Richard), 1894-1962--Correspondence.; Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1892-1971.; Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1892-1971. Man's nature and his communities: essays on the dynamics and enigmas of man's personal and social existence. 1965.; Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1892-1971. Pious and secular America. 1958.; Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1892-1971. Self and the dramas of history. 1955.; Niebuhr, Ursula. Ursula Niebuhr papers.; Paton, Alan--Correspondence.; Pike, James A. (James Albert), 1913-1969--Correspondence.; Press, Samuel D.--Correspondence.; Robertson, D. B.--Correspondence.; Sacks, Oliver, 1933-2015--Correspondence.; Scarlett, William, 1883-1973--Correspondence.; Schlesinger, Arthur M. (Arthur Meier), 1888-1965--Correspondence.; Schlesinger, Arthur M., Jr. (Arthur Meier), 1917-2007--Correspondence.; Stansgate, Margaret, 1897-1991--Correspondence.; Stevenson, Adlai E. (Adlai Ewing), 1900-1965--Correspondence.; Stone, Ronald H.--Correspondence.; Tillich, Paul, 1886-1965--Correspondence.; Van Dusen, Henry P. (Henry Pitney), 1897-1975--Correspondence.; Van Husen, Geraldine--Correspondence.; Van Husen, Hugh--Correspondence.; Visser 't Hooft, Willem Adolph, 1900-1985--Correspondence.; Woodward, E. L. (Ernest Llewellyn), 1890-1971--Correspondence.
Organizations
Americans for Democratic Action--Correspondence.; CARE Inc.; Commission on Freedom of the Press--Correspondence.; Delta Cooperative Farm Project (Hillhouse, Miss.); Evangelical and Reformed Church.; Jerusalem Committee.; National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America--Correspondence.; Socialist Party (Tenn.). Committee on Economic and Racial Justice.; U.S. National Commission for UNESCO.; Union for Democratic Action--Correspondence.; United States. Commission on Cultural Affairs in Occupied Territories.; University of Edinburgh.; World Council of Churches--Correspondence.
Subjects
Agriculture--Massachusetts--Hillhouse.; Ethics.; Labor.; Political ethics.; Race relations.; Religion and social problems.; Religion.; Social problems.; Social service.; Socialism.; Theology.; World politics--20th century.
Places
Europe--Description and travel.; Germany--Description and travel.; Tennessee--Economic conditions.; Tennessee--Race relations.
Titles
New republic.; New York times.; Saturday review of literature.
Occupations
Authors.; Philosophers.; Theologians.
Acquisition Information
The papers of Reinhold Niebuhr, theologian, philosopher, and author, were given to the Library of Congress by Niebuhr in 1965. Additions were given by Reinhold and Ursula Niebuhr and others from 1965 through 2009.
Transfers
Most photographs have been transferred to the custody of the Library's Prints and Photographs Division, where they are identified as part of these papers.
Related Material
Other collections in the Manuscript Division that contain papers of Reinhold Niebuhr include those of Raymond Leslie Buell, the Fund for the Reinhold Niebuhr Award, Hans J. Morgenthau, Paul F. Sifton and Claire G. Sifton, and Charles P. Taft.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Reinhold Niebuhr are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1892, June 21 Born, Wright City, Mo.
1910 Graduated, Elmhurst College, Elmhurst, Ill.
1913 Graduated, Eden Theological Seminary, Webster Groves, Mo. Ordained minister, German Evangelical Synod of North America
1914 B. D., Yale University Divinity School, New Haven, Conn.
1915 A. M., Yale University Divinity School, New Haven, Conn.
1915 1928 Pastor, Bethel Evangelical Church, Detroit, Mich.
1929 Published Leaves from the Notebook of a Tamed Cynic. Chicago: Willett, Clark and Colby
1928 1930 Associate professor of Christian ethics and philosophy of religion, Union Theological Seminary, New York, N.Y.
1930 1960 Professor of Christian ethics and philosophy of religion, Union Theological Seminary, New York, N.Y.
1931 Married Ursula Keppel-Compton
1932 Published Moral Man and Immoral Society. New York, N.Y.: C. Scribner's Sons
1939 Delivered the Gifford Lectures at the University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, Scotland; published in 1941-1943 as The Nature and Destiny of Man. New York, N.Y.: C. Scribner's Sons. 2 vols.
1940 Resigned from the Socialist Party
1941 1966 Editor, Christianity and Crisis
1947 Co-chairman, Founding Conference of Americans for Democratic Action
1964 Received Presidential Medal of Freedom
1971, June 1 Died, Stockbridge, Mass.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Reinhold Niebuhr (1892-1971) span the years 1907-1997, with the bulk of the material concentrated in the period from the 1930s through the 1980s. The collection portrays the range of Niebuhr's work and his influence in twentieth-century theology, politics, and society. Included are correspondence, articles, sermons, reviews, lectures, typescripts of books, biographical material, printed matter, and miscellaneous items. The original collection is arranged in the following series: Correspondence, Speech, Article, and Book File, Miscellany, June Bingham Correspondence, Reinhold Niebuhr Correspondence Collected by June Bingham, June Bingham Book File, and William Scarlett Correspondence. Five separate additions to Niebuhr's papers have been organized and appended to the original collection. These additions are listed and described in the order of their receipt in the Manuscript Division.
Correspondence with a wide array of theologians, political leaders, academicians, literary figures, and diverse community leaders and organizations comprises a substantial portion of the original collection and Additions I and II. Focusing chiefly on Niebuhr's theological interests and work, much of the material relates his efforts to apply religion and ethical standards to social and political problems. Two such examples, represented in depth, are the papers concerning the Delta Cooperative Farm Project and the Committee on Economic and Racial Justice. Some of the prominent or frequent correspondents include W. H. Auden, Jacques Barzun, John C. Bennett, Dietrich Bonhoeffer, Tom C. Clark, Henry Sloane Coffin, James Bryant Conant, Sherwood Eddy, Dwight D. Eisenhower, T. S. Eliot, Felix Frankfurter, Hubert H. Humphrey, James A. Pike, Samuel D. Press, William Scarlett, Arthur M. Schlesinger (1917-2007), Adlai E. Stevenson (1900-1965), Paul Tillich, Henry P. Van Dusen, and Willem Adolph Visser't Hooft. Also included is a sizable amount of correspondence with such organizations as Americans for Democratic Action, Commission on Freedom of the Press, National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America, Union for Democratic Action, and the World Council of Churches.
There are numerous outlines of sermons delivered by Niebuhr and typescripts of articles ranging in subject matter from national and international political affairs to labor and race relations, theology, and economics. There are also typescripts and related correspondence dealing with book reviews Niebuhr wrote for the New York Times, Saturday Review, New Republic, and other publications. Typescripts of three of Niebuhr's books, Man's Nature and His Communities, Pious and Secular America, and The Self and the Dramas of History, are also included.
The collection also contains outlines of class lectures, engagement calendars, bibliographies of Niebuhr's published works, and miscellaneous oversize materials.
Papers presented to the Library by June Bingham relate to her research conducted while preparing a biography of Niebuhr, Courage to Change: An Introduction to the Life and Thought of Reinhold Niebuhr, and include her correspondence as well as assorted correspondence by Niebuhr that she collected.
Addition III is composed primarily of correspondence, subject files, and writings collected and maintained by Ursula Niebuhr. Although the papers include a few letters to and from Niebuhr during the last years of his life, the material consists chiefly of Ursula Niebuhr's correspondence with academic colleagues, researchers, and family friends. Also of interest are letters from her friends and colleagues in England describing conditions there during World War II. Subject files contain research material collected by the Niebuhrs, biographical clippings, information on colleagues, and material related to researchers studying Niebuhr, including a group of letters exchanged with Richard Fox and others relating to his 1985 book, Reinhold Niebuhr: A Biography. The writings file includes articles, addresses, notes, reviews and other miscellaneous writings by Niebuhr. Prominent or frequent correspondents include John Barnes, John C. Bennett, Isaiah Berlin, Jimmy Carter, Paul D. Clasper, Isobel Cripps, Sir Richard Stafford Cripps, T. S. Eliot, Felix Frankfurter, J. King Gordon, Ruth Anderson Gordon, Ronald O. Hall, Will Herberg, Hubert H. Humphrey, Franklin H. Littell, Daniel P. Moynihan, Alan Paton, D. B. Robertson, Arthur M. Schlesinger (1917-2007), Ronald H. Stone, Hugh Van Husen, Geraldine Van Husen, and E. L. Woodward.
Addition IV also includes a significant group of family correspondence and professional files of Ursula Niebuhr. Letters exchanged by Reinhold and Ursula Niebuhr during the 1930s comprise the bulk of the family correspondence and provide insight into Niebuhr's political and social activities. Highlights in the correspondence include Niebuhr's descriptions of activities relating to his Gifford lectures at the University of Edinburgh (1939), his travels to Germany with the U.S. Commission on Cultural Affairs in Occupied Territories (1946), and other trips to Europe during the late 1940s. Also included are letters Niebuhr received from his brother, H. Richard Niebuhr, during the 1930s. In 1991, Ursula Niebuhr edited and published much of this correspondence in Remembering Reinhold Niebuhr ([San Francisco]: HarperSanFrancisco). Ursula Niebuhr's professional files include correspondence, articles, essays, newspapers columns, speeches, lectures, prayers, and sermon outlines. The correspondence relates to theological and personal matters and includes a scattering of letters by her husband. Significant or frequent correspondents include Tony Benn, Isobel Cripps, Sam H. Franklin, George F. Kennan, Teddy Kollek, Archibald MacLeish, Norman Mailer, Martin E. Marty, George S. McGovern, Hans J. Morgenthau, Oliver W. Sacks, Arthur M. Schlesinger (1917-2007), and Margaret Stansgate.
Addition V complements the material in Additions III and IV and is composed of correspondence, subject files, and writings. Significant correspondents include David Amiran, Ruth Amiran, Jonathan Bingham, June Bingham, Teddy Kollek, and Ronald H. Stone. The subject file details Ursula Niebuhr's work with the Jerusalem Committee and study of Christian liturgy. The writings file contains articles by both Reinhold and Ursula Niebuhr. The writings file also contains an outline entitled "The Significance of Luther's Dfisnce [Defiance] of the Pope" that Reinhold Niebuhr was working on at the time of his death.
Organization of the Papers
The collection is arranged in twelve series:
Correspondence, 1918-1961
Speech, Article, and Book File, 1913-1965
Miscellany
June Bingham Correspondence
Reinhold Niebuhr Correspondence Collected by June Bingham
June Bingham Book File
William Scarlett Correspondence, 1958-1971
Addition I, 1914-1976
Addition II, 1930-1972
Addition III, 1907-1992
Addition IV, 1913-1994
Addition V, 1910-1997
Container List
- Correspondence, 1918-1961 (Box 1-13)
  Letters sent and received.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Aldrich, Winthrop W. (Box 1)
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters
  - American Association for Democratic Germany
  - American Committee for Christian Refugees, Inc.
  - American Committee for Cultural Freedom
  - American Committee on Africa
  - American Library Association
  - Americans for Democratic Action
  - Armstrong, Hamilton Fish
  - "A" miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Baldwin, Roger
  - Barzun, Jacques
  - Benton, William A.
  - Blake, Eugene Carson
  - Bonhoeffer, Dietrich
  - Bowles, Chester
  - Brown, Thatcher M.
  - Brownell, Herbert
  - Bundy, McGeorge
  - Burnett, Whit
  - Butler, Pierce
  - "B" miscellaneous
  - Charles Scribner's Sons See Container 11, Scribner's Sons, Charles
  - Christian Action
  - Christianity and Society
  - Clark, Tom C. (Box 3)
  - Coffin, Henry Sloane
  - Columbia University, New York, N.Y.
  - Commission on Freedom of the Press
  - Commission on the Occupied Areas
  - Committee on Economic and Racial Justice
  - Conant, James Bryant
  - Congress of European American Associations
  - Cooperative for American Remittances to Europe
  - Council on Foreign Relations
  - Croly, Herbert David
  - Cutting, Bronson
  - "Ca - Ci" miscellaneous
  - "Cl - Cu" miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Delta Cooperative Farm Project, Rochdale, Miss.
  - Douglas, Helen Gahagan
  - Du Bois, W. E. B.
  - Dubinsky, David
  - Dulles, Allen
  - Dulles, John Foster
  - Dun, Angus
  - "D" miscellaneous
  - Eddy, Sherwood (Box 5)
  - Eden Theological Seminary, Webster Groves, Mo.
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D.
  - Eliot, T. S. See same series Faber and Faber Ltd.
  - Elliston, Herbert Berridge
  - Elson, Edward L. R.
  - Emergency Rescue Committee
  - European Student Service Fund
  - "E" miscellaneous
  - Faber and Faber Ltd.
  - Farrar, John
  - Farrell, James T.
  - Fast, Howard
  - Federal Council of the Churches of Christ in America
  - Fellowship of Southern Churchmen
  - Flanders, Ralph E.
  - Frank, Jerome (Box 6)
  - Frank, Waldo David
  - Frankfurter, Felix
  - Freedom House
  - "F" miscellaneous
  - Gollancz, Victor
  - Gruening, Ernest
  - "G" miscellaneous
  - Hall of Fame, New York University, New York, N.Y.
  - Harriman, W. Averell
  - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass.
  - Harvard University Divinity School, Cambridge, Mass.
  - Hase, Hans Christoph von
  - Haydn, Hiram Collins
  - Hocking, William Ernest
  - Holmes, John Haynes
  - Hoover, J. Edgar
  - Hughes, Emmet J.
  - Humphrey, Hubert H.
  - Hutchins, Robert Maynard (Box 7)
  - Huxley, Julian
  - "H" miscellaneous
  - Infantry Journal
  - Institute for Advanced Study
  - International Rescue Committee
  - "I" miscellaneous
  - James Nisbet & Co.
  - Javits, Jacob J.
  - Jessup, Philip C.
  - "J" miscellaneous
  - Katzenbach, Nicholas deB.
  - Kirchwey, Freda
  - Kirk, Grayson
  - Knopf, Alfred A.
  - "Ka - Kn" miscellaneous
  - "Ko - Kw" miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Lehman, Herbert H.
  - Lerner, Max
  - Link, Henry C.
  - Loyal Americans of German Descent
  - Luce, Henry R.
  - "L" miscellaneous
  - Mann, Erika
  - Markel, Lester
  - McCloy, John J.
  - "Mc" miscellaneous
  - Mead, Margaret
  - Millikan, Robert A.
  - Milton, George Fort
  - Morgenthau, Hans J.
  - Murphy, Frank
  - Murry, John Middleton
  - "Ma - Me" miscellaneous
  - "Mi - My" miscellaneous (Box 9)
  - Nation
  - National Committee for Resettlement of Foreign Physicians
  - National Committee for the Rights of the Choolokian Family
  - National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America
  - National Mental Health Foundation
  - New School for Social Research, New York, N.Y.
  - Niebuhr, H. Richard
  - Niemoller, D. Martin
  - "Na - Ni" miscellaneous
  - "No" miscellaneous (Box 10)
  - Oxnam, G. Bromley
  - "O" miscellaneous
  - Philbrick, Herbert A.
  - Pike, James A.
  - "P" miscellaneous
  - "Q" miscellaneous
  - Rauh, Joseph L.
  - Religious News Service
  - Reston, James
  - Rockefeller Foundation
  - "R" miscellaneous
  - Schlesinger, Arthur M. (1917-2007)
  - Schweitzer, Albert
  - Scribner's Sons, Charles (Box 11)
  - Sedgwick, Ellery
  - Shuster, George
  - Sinclair, Upton
  - Sobell, Helen
  - Sproul, Robert Gordon
  - Stevenson, Adlai E. (1900-1965)
  - Streibert, Theodore C.
  - Student Christian Movement of Great Britain and Ireland
  - "S" miscellaneous
  - Thomas, Norman (Box 12)
  - Thompson, Dorothy
  - Tillich, Paul
  - "T" miscellaneous
  - Union for Democratic Action
  - Union Theological Seminary, New York, N.Y.
  - U. S. National Commission for UNESCO
  - "U" miscellaneous
  - Van Dusen, Henry P. (Box 13)
  - Visser't Hooft, Willem Adolph
  - "V" miscellaneous
  - Wechsler, James
  - Welles, Sumner
  - White, William Allen
  - Wise, Stephen S.
  - World Council of Churches
  - World Student Service Fund
  - "W" miscellaneous
  - "Y - Z" miscellaneous
  - Unidentified correspondence
- Speech, Article, and Book File, 1913-1965 (Box 14-23)
  Speeches, sermons, articles, book reviews, and book manuscripts.
  Grouped by type of material and arranged alphabetically within groups, with the exception of sermons which are untitled and undated.
  - Speeches (Box 14)
  - Sermons
  - Articles (Box 15)
    - "America: A Nation with Imperial Powers"
    - "America's Spiritual Resources for International Cooperation"
    - "The Anamoly of European Socialism"
    - "An Apology for the Intolerance of Conservatism"
    - "The Architecture of American Churches"
    - "Are We Drifting Back to Literalism and Individualism?"
    - "Asia First and America First"
    - "The Asian and African Battlegrounds between Communism and Democracy"
    - "Balanced Judgement and the Democratic Life"
    - "The Battles We Have Lost Since the Summit Meeting in Geneva"
    - "The Beria Confession"
    - "Biblical Faith and Socialism"
    - "The Cardinal and Communism"
    - "The Cause and Cure of the American Psychosis"
    - "China and the United Nations"
    - "The Christian Faith and the Christian Church"
    - "A Christian Political Party"
    - "Christianity and Darwin's Revolution"
    - "Christianity and the Moral Law"
    - "The Church as a Community of Grace"
    - "The Church Versus the Gospel"
    - "The Civil Rights Issue and the Democratic Convention"
    - "Clericalism and Anti-Clericalism"
    - "Co-Existence and Semantics"
    - "Comments on the Religious Assumptions of Adam Smith and Karl Marx"
    - "The Concept of 'Order of Creation' in Emil Brunner's Social Ethic"
    - "Conservatism and Liberalism in America"
    - "Coronation Afterthoughts on Poetry and Politics"
    - "The Cult of the Automobile"
    - "The Cultural Crisis of Our Age"
    - "Das Rassenproblem in Amerika"
    - "Democracy and Foreign Policy"
    - "Democracy and the Party Spirit"
    - "The Efficacy and Limits of Military Power"
    - "The Eisenhower Doctrine: Everything in General and Nothing in Particular"
    - "The Eisenhower Myth"
    - "Eisenhower's Theory of Power and Morals in Politics"
    - "The End of an Era in Labor Relations"
    - "The English and the Germans"
    - "The Ethics of Loyalty"
    - "Europe's and Asia's Anti-Americanism"
    - "Fascism and the Middle Classes"
    - "The Fate of European Socialism"
    - "Freedom"
    - "The French Don't Like Us"
    - "Freud and the Problem of the Relation of Creativity and Self-Concern"
    - "The Frustrations of a Powerful Nation"
    - "General De Gaulle and France"
    - "God in History" (Box 16)
    - "The God Who Has Become the Devil"
    - "Is God Good Or Is He Omnipotent?"
    - "Is Good an Obstacle to the Better?"
    - "Higher Education in America"
    - "History As Drama"
    - "Human Destiny and History"
    - "The Hydrogen Bomb"
    - "The Illusions about the Efficacy of Summit Meetings"
    - "The Impulse for Perfection and the Impulse for Community"
    - "India, America, and the East-West Struggle"
    - "The Intellectuals, the Administration and the Marxist Heresy"
    - "The Irony of the Struggle between Communism and Democracy"
    - "The Irrational in Politics"
    - "Is Historical Analogy Possible?"
    - "Kinsey and the Moral Problem of Man's Sexual Life"
    - "Khrushchev and the Cold War"
    - "Lewis Mumford"
    - "Liberty as Necessity and Luxury"
    - "Love and Justice"
    - "Love and Law in Protestantism and Catholicism"
    - "The Merger of the C.I.O. and the A.F.L. and the Social History behind It"
    - "The Middle East"
    - "The Moral and Political Philosophy behind the 'Right to Work' Laws"
    - "Moral and Religious Problems in an Economy of Abundance"
    - "The Moral and Spiritual Content of the Atlantic Community"
    - "The Moral Issue in International Relations"
    - "Moral Re-Armament"
    - "Mystery and Meaning"
    - "The National Interest and International Responsibility"
    - "New Wine in Old Bottles and Old Wine in New Bottles"
    - "Observations on 'The Chinese Wall'"
    - "On Being Judged by an Evil Judge"
    - "Our Stake in the State of Israel"
    - "Patriotism and Altruism"
    - "The Phenomenon of President Eisenhower"
    - "Portrait of an Idealist"
    - "The President Will Run"
    - "Preventive War"
    - "The Problem of Man's Finiteness, Freedom and Self-Concern"
    - "The Problem of Nuclear Warfare"
    - "A Proposal for Billy Graham"